racer.com 2012-05-20

# Privacy Policy - Racer.com

## Privacy Policy

**Last updated: May 2012**

US Privacy Policy | International Privacy Policy

## US Privacy Policy

Haymarket Media Inc. ("Haymarket") has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to protect your privacy and to fully disclose what information we collect and how we use it. Please note your use of our Digital Offering is also governed by the Terms and Conditions of use. 

**Information Collection and Dissemination**

**General Principles**

  * In general, you may visit this Digital Offering or use the companion mobile applications (collectively referred to as the ÒDigital OfferingÓ)without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. 
  * As you browse our Digital Offering, the Digital Offering collects log file, IP address of your computer, and other standard tracking data we use to evaluate Digital Offering traffic and usage patterns. Such information is aggregated with tracking data from all Digital Offering visitors. We will use the information to personalize the Digital Offering according to your preferences based on the aggregated information. We also use the aggregated information to evaluate products and services we may offer to you. 
  * Some portions of this Digital Offering may require you to give us personally identifiable information such as your name, job title, company, physical mailing address, e-mail address, telephone and fax numbers (Personal Information) and, if applicable, financial information such as your credit card information (Financial Information), for, without limitation, (i) registration for attendance at certain Haymarket trade shows, conferences and events; and (ii) subscriptions to our publications. If you communicate with us by e-mail, post messages to any of our chat groups, bulletin boards or forums, or otherwise complete online forms, surveys or contest entries, any information provided in such communications may be collected as Personal Information. 
  * If you elect to provide us Personal Information, we use it primarily to deliver the service you requested. Other uses of Personal Information are described elsewhere in this Policy.
  * If you submit Financial Information, we use that information primarily to verify your credit and collect payments for your purchases, orders, registrations etc. 
  * Haymarket uses a third party to process credit card transactions and does not store financial information, such as credit card information on its website. We do retain the last four digits of the credit card number solely for customer service purposes. 

**Information Sharing**

Unless you opt-out, we share your Personal Information with Haymarket's affiliates and partners and third parties licensed to access your Personal Information by any of the foregoing. To opt-out, send us an email to [Newlettersupport@haymarketmedia.com](mailto:Newlettersupport@haymarketmedia.com)

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will keep your Personal Information and your Financial Information private and will not share it with third parties, unless such disclosure is necessary t (a) comply with a court order or other legal process; (b) protect our rights or property; or (c) enforce our terms of service. 

Several companies unaffiliated with Haymarket provide email deployment services for our email messages. The personally identifiable information, such as e-mail address, we provide to these vendors for the purposes of e-mail deployment is only used by them for that purpose and not for any other business activity. 

In order to comply with the Federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003, we also may provide lists of customers who have opted-out of email promotion for Haymarket products to other companies, so they can be suppressed from mailings those companies send on Haymarket’s behalf. In addition, if you unsubscribe from a mailing we send to our own list on behalf of a third party, your removal instruction may also be supplied to the third party and added to their own suppression file. If you continue receiving email after opting out, please contact us at web@haymarketmedia.com. 

**Aggregated information**

We sometimes provide aggregated usage or tracking information collected from this Digital Offering to third parties. 

**Information on Children**

As a business-to-business company, we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. On-line registration and Digital Offering usage is restricted to adults who are professionally engaged in the businesses we serve. 

**Updating Visitor Information:**

You have the option of accessing, correcting, updating and modifying your Personal and/or Financial Information, or visitor profile, at any time and as often as desired. If you desire to delete your Personal and/or Financial Information please contact us at web@haymarketmedia.com. 

**Update Your Newsletter Subscriptions**

You can opt-in to newsletter mailing lists, or remove yourself (opt-out) at any time through the subscription management page (this page will display all of your newsletter subscriptions) or by following the instructions at the end of the newsletters you receive. Please allow 3-5 business days for changes to take effect. You can locate the subscription management page through the “Log In” link at the top right hand corner of the Digital Offering. For Haymarket Digital Offerings not offering the subscription management page, please send your email preferences to subscriptions@haymarketmedia.com. 

**Update Your Print Subscription Information**

You can correct or change your print subscription information by sending an email to subscriptions@haymarketmedia.com. Please allow 2-4 weeks for changes to take effect. 

**Third Party and Affiliated Links:**

Our Digital Offerings contain external links to other Digital Offerings including suppliers, advertisers and affiliates. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the content of, or information gathered by, these other Digital Offerings. We do not endorse any of these Digital Offerings or the products or services associated with such Digital Offerings merely because they are linked to our Digital Offering. 

**Haymarket Magazines, Seminars, Events, Sites and Other Publications and Services**

As a Haymarket customer you can also expect to receive relevant email and postal offers for Haymarket publications, seminars, events, Digital Offerings and other services. From time to time we are also able to secure and offer to our customers specially-negotiated discounts and new products from other leading companies. If you would prefer not to receive such mailings in the future, you can change your preference via the subscription management page which can be located by using the “Log In” link at the top right hand corner of the Digital Offering. For Haymarket Digital Offerings not offering the subscription management page, please send your email preferences to subscriptions@haymarketmedia.com. 

**Haymarket Events**

Haymarket Events are produced for a variety of companies (Sponsors). All data collected during the registration of such events may be shared with those Sponsors. This data is governed by the individual Sponsor's privacy policy and may be used by the Sponsor for follow-up purposes. Please visit the Sponsor’s web site to review its privacy policy. Similarly, Haymarket events will have the same access to this data as the Sponsors, and this Privacy Policy continues to govern how Haymarket uses the data. For details on how event Sponsors use the information you provide, please contact the Sponsor directly.

If you have any questions, please contact Events@haymarketmedia.com.

**Haymarket eSeminars**

Haymarket eSeminars produces sponsored webcasts and online trade shows for a variety of Sponsors. All data collected during the registration for such events will be shared with those Sponsors. This data is governed by the individual Sponsor's privacy policy and may be used by the Sponsor for follow-up purposes. Please visit the Sponsor’s web site to review its privacy policy. Similarly, Haymarket eSeminars will have the same access to this data as the Sponsors, and this Privacy Policy continues to govern how Haymarket uses the data. For details on how eSeminar Sponsors use the information you provide, please contact the Sponsor directly.

Haymarket eSeminars also automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, Internet connection speed, Internet connection duration, and Real Media and Windows Media player information. This is done in conjunction with our broadcast providers. Your data is collected and retained by our broadcast providers for the sole purposes of delivering eSeminars content appropriately, traffic reporting, and enabling re-registration for future events. In addition, our broadcast providers use cookie technology to identify you as a registered user of the eSeminars service.

If you have any questions, please contact eSeminars@haymarketmedia.com.

**Email A Friend**

If you choose to use our referral service to inform a friend about our Digital Offering, products, or services, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will send your friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the Digital Offering. We may store this information for the purpose of sending this one-time e-mail and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact the us at web@haymarketmedia.com to have their information removed from our database. 

**Online Ad Serving**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Digital Offering. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this Digital Offering and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: [ http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp)

**Cookies**

A "cookie" is a bit of data sent by a Web site through the browser to the computer of the user visiting the site, and enables the site to return the results the browser expects. Haymarket uses temporary, session-specific cookies to ensure visits to its Web site are smooth and customized for the visitor. Such cookies allow us to provide a visitor's browser with information tailored to the visitor's preferences and needs. Haymarket also uses permanent or persistent cookies that remain on a visitor's computer after the visitor leaves a Haymarket Web site. 

If you do not want your browser to accept cookies, you can turn off the cookie acceptance option in the browser's settings. However, disabling the cookie support function of the browser will prevent our Web site from functioning properly and you may not be able to utilize fully all of the site's features and information. 

We use advertising companies to develop banner ads for our Digital Offering. These ads may contain cookies. These companies collect cookies sent to your browser through the banner ads and we do not have control or access to this data. Information may be collected from a third party through the use of cookies and web beacons to measure website traffic. 

**Pixel Tags**

Like many web sites, Haymarket may also use pixel tags, also known as beacons, spotlight tags or web bugs, to improve our understanding of site traffic, visitor behavior, and response to promotional campaigns, as a supplement to our server logs and other methods of traffic and response measurement. Pixel tags are sometimes used in conjunction with small Javascript-based applications, also for the purpose of traffic measurement. We may also implement pixel tags provided by other companies, for the same purpose. You can disable pixel tags by changing your browser settings to omit images and disable Javascript; or there are commercial software packages available that can omit pixel tags and most advertisements. 

**Opt-out Option**

Visitors to this Digital Offering can decide if they want to receive promotional information from Haymarket. On the visitor registration pages, prospective visitors can choose to request Haymarket not to e-mail them advertising and promotional information. Should visitors accept promotional e-mail from Haymarket, any e-mail they receive will include instructions on how to be removed from Haymarket's promotional e-mail list. If you continue receiving email after opting out, please contact us at web@haymarketmedia.com. 

**Security and Encryption**

This Digital Offering takes commercially reasonable precautions to protect your information. When appropriate, we use SSL encryption technology on our Digital Offering and a secure server to encrypt information transmitted between your browsers and our server. As a result, data you submit to our Digital Offering such as credit card and payment information is transmitted using commercially reasonable security over the Internet. 

This Digital Offering also uses password encryption to keep ensure your privacy when registering for newsletters, events, and other Haymarket related media.

**Notification of Changes**

Haymarket reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the Digital Offering. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Digital Offering. Please check back often to review the latest version of our Privacy Policy.

**Your Acceptance of these Terms**

By using our Digital Offering, products or services, you signify your acceptance of the terms of the Haymarket Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of the Haymarket Privacy Policy, please do not use the Digital Offering, products and/or services and exit the Digital Offering immediately.

**Questions?**

If you have any questions on our Privacy Policy, or complaints about our handling of your Personal and/or Financial Information, you can contact us at [sitefeedback@haymarketmedia.com](mailto:sitefeedback@haymarketmedia.com).

## International Privacy Policy

This privacy policy sets out the basis on which your personal data will be processed by us as the data controller of your personal data for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 ("the Act"). Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat them.

### Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Digital Offering. This includes information provided at the time of registration or at the time of posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by Haymarket or when you report a problem with the Digital Offering.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * Haymarket may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of your visits to the Digital Offering and the resources that you access.

### IP Addresses and Cookies

“Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a website. Haymarket uses cookies to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our sites. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies, but please be aware that for some parts of our sites to work, you will need to accept cookies. For more information please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

Following recent revisions of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 relating to the notification and use of cookies we are currently working towards implementing the new requirements in line with guidance provided by The Information Commissioner’s Office. 

### Where we store your personal data

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have provided you with a password, which enables you to access certain parts of the Digital Offering, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. As stated above, it is important you do not share your password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. So, whilst we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot ensure the security of data transmitted by you to the Digital Offering. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information we will use security procedures and features to prevent unauthorised access to it. 

### Uses made of the information

We may use information held about you in the following ways:

  * to ensure that the Digital Offering's content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer
  * to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you; if you would prefer not to have your email address used in this way please let us know by sending an email to sitefeedback@haymarket.com
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service where you
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service where you choose to do so;
  * to notify you about changes to our service.

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries as defined in section 736 of the Company Act 1985.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * in the event that we offer to sell any assets in which case we may disclose your personal data to the potential purchaser of such assets;
  * if substantially all of Haymarket's assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by us about our customers will be transferred to such third party;
  * if we are required to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions or any other agreement; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Haymarket, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for protection against credit risk and fraud.

We do not disclose individual information to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users. We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. We would comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience using the personal data we have collected from you and from others. 

### Your rights

You have the right to request us not to disclose any of your personal data or information or to pass information to third parties. We will usually inform you before collecting your data, if we intend to disclose your information to any third party and you can exercise that right by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also notify us by contacting us at [sitefeedback@haymarketmedia.com](mailto:sitefeedback@haymarketmedia.com).

The Digital Offering may from time to time contain links to and from partner and/or affiliate websites. If you follow a link to their sites, please note that these sites have their own privacy policy and that Haymarket does not accept any responsibility or liability for protection of personal data which you may submit to a third party's site. You are recommended to check the wording of the relevant privacy policies before you submit any personal data to those sites. 

### Access to information

The Act gives you various rights including the right to access information held about you. Questions about this privacy policy can be addressed to [sitefeedback@haymarketmedia.com](mailto:sitefeedback@haymarketmedia.com).
